https://weybridgeurc.org.uk/privacy-policy/

Skip to content
DATA PRIVACY STATEMENTWeybridge United Reformed Church1. Personal dataPersonal data relates to a living individual who can be identified from that data. Identification can be by the information alone or in conjunction with any other information in the data controller’s possession or likely to come into such possession. The processing of personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (the ‘GDPR’).2. Data Controller The eldership (serving elders) of Weybridge United Reformed Church is the data controller (contact details below). This means it decides how your personal data is processed and for what purposes.3. How do we process your personal data?The eldership of Weybridge United Reformed Church complies with its obligations under the “GDPR” by keeping personal data up to date; by storing and destroying it securely; by not collecting or retaining excessive amounts of data; by protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure and by ensuring that appropriate technical measures are in place to protect personal data.We use personal data for the following purposes: –to administer membership records;to maintain our financial accounts and records (including the processing of gift aid);to provide news and information about events, activities and services at the church;to fundraise and promote the interests of the church; to manage [employees and] volunteers; to enable the church to provide voluntary services for the benefit of the public in our local community;to provide contact details of officers and others with specific responsibilities (eg DBS signatories) to the synod office and Church House. This enables the synod and national administration of the United Reformed Church.4. What is the legal basis for processing your personal data?Processing is carried out by a not-for-profit body with a political, philosophical, religious or trade union aim provided: –the processing relates only to members or former members (or those who have regular contact with it in connection with those purposes); and there is no disclosure to a third party without consent; orProcessing is necessary for carrying out obligations under employment, social security or social protection law, or a collective agreement; orExplicit consent of the data subject has been given.5. Sharing personal dataYour personal data will be treated as strictly confidential and will only be shared with other members of the church in order to carry out a service to other church members or for purposes connected with the church. We will only share your data with third parties with your consent.6. How long do we keep data?We retain data on the following basis:Record TypeRetention PeriodMembership rollsIndefinitelyMembers, adherents and friends contact details24 months after the last contactJunior Church rolluntil the child/young adult reaches the age of 21.Junior Church contacts24 months after the last contactCradle rollIndefinitelyGift aid declarations and paperwork6 years after the calendar year to which it relatesRegisters of Marriage As required by the Registrar GeneralRegister of BaptismsIndefinitelyRegister of FuneralsIndefinitelyGrave RecordsIndefinitelyPersonal data relating to events for which additional information is gathered eg Church holidays Disposed of immediately after the event unless anything has occurred (eg and accident) which indicates that records should be retained for a longer period.Records of attendance of children/young people and helpersIndefinitely for safeguarding purposesPhotographs and videos of events24 months after the event – selected items retained for historical recordsInsurance RecordsIndefinitelySafeguarding mattersIndefinitely or until advised otherwise by authoritiesAccident Books3 years from the date of the last entry (or, if the accident involves a child/ young adult, then until that person reaches the age of 21)Complaints (non -safeguarding)3 years after resolution of complaint (unless further action is anticipated)Minute BooksIndefinitelyEmployee Records6 years after the date of termination of employmentPension Records (money purchase)6 years after transfer or value takenVisitors BooksOther RecordChurch Directory- Reviewed Annually7. Your rights and your personal data Unless subject to an exemption under the GDPR, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data: –The right to request a copy of the personal data which Weybridge United Reformed Church holds about you (a Subject Access Request or ‘SAR’); The right to request that the eldership of Weybridge United Reformed Church corrects any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date; The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for Weybridge United Reformed Church to retain such data;The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time;The right to request that the data controller provide you with your personal data and where possible, to transmit that data directly to another data controller.The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;The right to object to the processing of personal data;The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioners Office.8. Further processingIf we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by this Data Protection Notice, then we will provide you with a new notice explaining this new use prior to commencing the processing and setting out the relevant purposes and processing conditions. Where and whenever necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new processing.9. Contact DetailsTo exercise all relevant rights, queries of complaints please in the first instance contact the Church Secretary at Weybridge United Reformed Church .You can contact the Information Commissioners Office on 0303 123 1113 or via email https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/ or at the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire. SK9 5AF.The EldersWeybridge United Reformed ChurchDate
